Introduction Video for Cycle Crossover.
We start with genotypes of two parents and
nothing else.
First thing is to find all cycles, select
the first index and the first parent and
check what value is contained in the second
parent at the same index.
Then we'll look for an index and the first
parent containing the previously selected
value. If the value is not yet present in
the cycle, we continue the process.
Otherwise, the cycle is finished.
After all, indexes are assigned to a cycle.
We can proceed with the next step.
Number all the cycles.
If the cyclist number is odd, copy the
values from the index included in the cycle,
from the first bar and otherwise copy the
values from the second parent.
The result is a genotype of a child
necessary for further steps of genetic
algorithm.