Introduction video for Partially Matched
Crossover.
We start with genotypes of two parents and
two parameters: first index and segment length.
For the genotype part specified by those
parameters, we rewrite the values from the
first parent. Now we proceed to fill the
missing values using the second parent.
First, we look at the indexes that were
already filled.
For each of those indexes, we take the value
from the second parent.
Look what value is at the same index of the
first parent and search for this value in the
second parent. And remember its index.
If that position in the child genome is
empty, we fill it with the value from the
second parent. Otherwise, we continue the
process until we find an empty spot.
If the value from the second parent is
already in the child genome, we ignore it.
After we are done with the steps for the
segment, we rewrite other unused values from
the second parent.
The result is a genotype of a child
necessary for further steps of genetic
algorithm.